<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on David Aikman</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on David Aikman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Cross-Validation!</title>
      <link>/2020/11/05/exploring-cross-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/11/05/exploring-cross-validation/</guid>
      <description>Here are some demonstrations of different cross-validation techniques. For a broad explanation of cross-validation, see the bottom of this post.
Simple Holdout Cross-ValidationRandomly splitting data into a training and testing set, once.
Repeated Cross-ValidationLeave-\(p\)-OutThis algorithm randomly selects \(p\) observations to exclude from the training set. These \(p\) observations constitute the testing set. This process is repeated until all possible combinations of \(p\) data-points have been used as a testing set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invisible Women: NHS Condition Descriptions</title>
      <link>/2020/06/23/invisible-women-nhs-web-scraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/23/invisible-women-nhs-web-scraping/</guid>
      <description>After reading Invisible Women, I happened to come across this article on WebMD about menstrual pain that lists risk factors like this:
&#34;The following circumstances may make a woman more likely to experience menstrual cramps:
She started her first period at an early age (younger than 11 years).
Her menstrual periods are heavy.
She is overweight or obese.
She smokes cigarettes or uses alcohol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>False Normality</title>
      <link>/2019/11/14/false-normality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/14/false-normality/</guid>
      <description>pre {max-height: 300px;overflow-y: auto;}pre[class] {max-height: 300px;}A lot of statistical tests assume normal distribution of raw data or residuals from predicted model outcomes. One way to check for normality is visual, using histograms or Q-Q plots. Another way is statistical.
Of the statistical tests of normality, the Shapiro-Wilk test is the most powerful. See Razali and Wah for further discussion about power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>